<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapters on Sketches of Snoak City</title>
    <link>/post.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapters on Sketches of Snoak City</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Smile of Paeony 3rdfield</title>
      <link>/01-the-smile-of-paeony-3rdfield.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/01-the-smile-of-paeony-3rdfield.html</guid>
      <description>The first one to be filmed (to use the archaic term) was spotted at dawn by a roving reconnaissance pod over Ratman’s Fork, a desolate spot where the rough edge of urban sprawl gave way to the broken shells of long-abandoned warehouses. The route of the old motorway was still just detectable under the accretion of brambles, weeds, hardy grasses and the detritus of ancient wreckage. The images were automatically filed at Central, but left unprocessed for some sixty days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foroquont&#39;s Maze</title>
      <link>/02-foroquonts-maze.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/02-foroquonts-maze.html</guid>
      <description>A starburst of globubbles signalled the start of the annual contest in Snoak City’s westernmost district of Whissit Fields. In the warm dusk the bright globes hung like a slowly expanding cluster of floating jewels, casting a network of overlapping colours over this year’s untested challenge that was Foroquont’s maze.
High above the maze’s central core an invisibly tethered pod its underside a non-reflective black beamed images of the selected contestants as they each made their way through the four separate entrance locks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Acquisition</title>
      <link>/03-an-acquisition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/03-an-acquisition.html</guid>
      <description>Across the Stirrow from Garrible Park a diffuse glow to the north and the faint brouhaha of mass derision testified that the week-end match was in progress at Praspafole Stadium. Statistically, the Snoak City team had a very consistent record, never having won on their home ground, and their loyal followers relished their weekend chance to taunt and jeer, vying with each other, within the established code of decency, to shout the choicest insults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smolehive’s Anakalyptoscope</title>
      <link>/04-smolehives-anakalyptoscope.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/04-smolehives-anakalyptoscope.html</guid>
      <description>It was one of Snoak City&amp;rsquo;s quieter attractions.
It might have been the effect of its comparative isolation, or the sparse external lighting, but the building, despite its unusual solidity, gave the appearance of being drab and possibly in need of repair. It was difficult to know exactly what needed to be fixed. The curving walls were of rough grey local stone, with patches of moss where it was less weathered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prutt&#39;s Game by Thyles Dudoriac - a review</title>
      <link>/05-prutts-game.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/05-prutts-game.html</guid>
      <description>Don B Levitt
At the outset we are confronted with news reports of simultaneous but disparate events: a crop failure in Bhutan, the death of an elderly American poet, the closure of a Chinese bicycle factory, an archaeological discovery on a remote Scottish island, rumours of vampirism in Omaha, Nebraska, an astronomical observation which appears to conflict with current cosmological theory.
Prutt, when not engaged in his musical researches, sampling exotic foods or avoiding amatory entanglements, is preoccupied with mastering a frustratingly absorbing game called Solversion, and pays little attention to daily news items unless they threaten imminent catastrophe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look at Greeming &amp; Trulph</title>
      <link>/06-a-closer-look-at-greeming-and-trulph.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/06-a-closer-look-at-greeming-and-trulph.html</guid>
      <description>The shop door opened with a melodious ping, gradually admitting a small boy walking backwards, his arms wrapped round a cardboard box which reached from waist to chin. Every few steps he had to perform an awkward hop as the box began to slip and needed to be pushed back up with a knee. Each time this occurred the contents of the box resonated with a mildly discordant tinkling, like a chandelier caught in a draught.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Excursion to Platport</title>
      <link>/07-an-excursion-to-platport.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/07-an-excursion-to-platport.html</guid>
      <description>The house was unnaturally quiet, thought Aoma Mylhirm, not for the first time, with that familiar unbidden maternal pang, as she spread cheesefruit paste on a humal leaf, letting it rest on the plate for a minute to allow the enzymes to interact.
It was late afternoon. Relvin, a senior engineer at the water-purification plant, was of course still at work, and she must soon get back to her designing, preferring to work in daylight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yesterday&#39;s Spoons</title>
      <link>/08-yesterdays-spoons.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/08-yesterdays-spoons.html</guid>
      <description>Morton Quanderpyre&amp;rsquo;s emotional range was relatively narrow, but within this confined spectrum he was well practiced. He had absolutely no trouble with disdain, indignation or indifference; they were the familiar background to his daily life. Smugness also came easily to him. Had he not built an empire by outsmarting others? It had simply been a process of making the right decisions. He had needed to learn how to use people, to probe for weaknesses and take advantage of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Man with Bronze Hair</title>
      <link>/09-the-man-with-bronze-hair.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/09-the-man-with-bronze-hair.html</guid>
      <description>A few of those involved in the unauthorized landscaping in Smatparrox knew the bronze-haired man as Farras Grein. They were well-motivated, and knew better than to discuss either their work or his identity with strangers. They were also well-paid, but this was incidental to the satisfaction afforded by the importance of what they jointly aimed to achieve. There was good reason for the secrecy of their activities.
Rural hamlets are sometimes described as ‘sleepy’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Change of Plan</title>
      <link>/10-another-change-of-plan.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/10-another-change-of-plan.html</guid>
      <description>Registered simply as the Trox Bequest, the extraordinary object identified as the wine cup of Relf was now on permanent display at the City Museum. The cost of ensuring the security of this fabulous exhibit had been considerable, but was easily outweighed by the sustained increase in sightseers and researchers from near and far, come to marvel at the survival of an object known for so long only from ancient records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farny&#39;s Place</title>
      <link>/11-farnys-place.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/11-farnys-place.html</guid>
      <description>Held in suspension by an unseen balance of forces the great globe hung low over the linked cluster of buildings in East Snoak. From a distance its surface appeared perfectly reflective, but closer to it displayed constantly swirling polychromatic patterns reminiscent of a soap-bubble. Every so often, to the delight of spectators, somewhere on its periphery vagrant trails of colour would coalesce, and a luminous blob would momentarily detach itself, before dissipating to leave a slowly fading rainbow glow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atacrast</title>
      <link>/12-atacrast.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/12-atacrast.html</guid>
      <description>At the insistence of a second arpeggio of descending chimes, Mosper Belk reluctantly put down his book and shuffled into the front hall to peer closely at the wall-screen. It displayed in his doorway the profiled image of an unfamiliar man clad in sombre grey, apart from a jaunty emerald trim at collar and cuffs. He held a slim black case. There was a relaxed dignity about his stance which betokened someone serious and self-assured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reunion</title>
      <link>/13-reunion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/13-reunion.html</guid>
      <description>149
What is that bizarre contraption thrumming purposefully northwards along Narpins Way, trailing wafts of hot copper, ripe peaches and aging fish?
It could only be Ruckney Plitter in his custom-built pre-SunCell landshrinker, heading back to Snoak for the annual reunion with Ma Wheggs. By pre-arrangement, on the first mutually convenient day in Spring a half dozen of her former lodgers, all contemporaries, returned for this celebratory event. It is unlikely that their respective paths would ever have crossed if they had not chosen to come to Snoak City from their scattered parental homes during those few formative years, drawing strength from the happy accident of each other’s company as they faced unknown vicissitudes at the start of their future careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Padratheleon’s Ghosts</title>
      <link>/14-padratheleons-ghosts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/14-padratheleons-ghosts.html</guid>
      <description>“He still looks crabby.”
“Brawk from Research says that’s one of his three natural expressions: basically, preoccupied, sullen and unconvinced. According to Brawk it’s difficult to distinguish one from the others.”
“These quizzicists are trained to be sceptical, I suppose.”
“He usually avoids interviews. I wonder what made him agree to this one.”
“You mean apart from Tessany’s charm and good looks?”
“And considerable skill. You have to admit she’s damn good at her job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncle Glussog’s Talent Parade, and Other Matters</title>
      <link>/15-uncle-glussogs-talent-parade-and-other-matters.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/15-uncle-glussogs-talent-parade-and-other-matters.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Flowers of silk shatter&amp;rdquo; Bambane Quossark
By mid-afternoon the rally in Fountain Square, which had begun in a desultory fashion around breakfast time, had already reached unusual proportions. Other than at local sporting events, citizens of Snoak were rarely given to boisterous public displays. At CenSec, a recon pod had swiftly been sent up to assess the situation. Fitful gusts of wind severely tested the efficiency of its stabilizers, but it was robustly built, and designed to withstand much tougher conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eavesdropping at Quoils</title>
      <link>/16-eavesdropping-at-quoils.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/16-eavesdropping-at-quoils.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A free droplet of liquid naturally assumes a spherical shape, which has the minimum surface area for a given volume. The equivalence of measurement of energy per unit area to force per unit length can be proven by dimensional analysis.&amp;quot; Farras Grein
Gawl and Rambersack sprawled in their accustomed seats by the window, engaged in one of their protractedly serious linguistic discussions. On this occasion it concerned the possible distinction between ‘drip’ and ‘drop’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pranswat Passes Through</title>
      <link>/17-pranswat-passes-through.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/17-pranswat-passes-through.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;There is no such thing as Accident; it is Destiny misnamed.&amp;quot; Cherth Pranswat of Sirisulsor, Omnant Exemplary of the Order of Seven Streams.
Snoak was on the whole a secular community, benignly tolerant of visitors professing beliefs based on ancient texts or exclusive revelations of the divine, provided that such visitors did not disturb the peace by seeking to convert the unenlightened. Nonetheless some of Snoak’s own citizens still found comfort in practices many would think superstitious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling the Heat: A Twice-told Tale</title>
      <link>/18-feeling-the-heat.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/18-feeling-the-heat.html</guid>
      <description>“Tell me where it is, Gyme, or your pretty friend here will suffer the same fate as Ormos and the others.”
Gyme forced himself not to glance over to where Silki was cowering. Behind his back his numb fingers were slippery, as an expertly modified thumbnail at last began to bite through tape instead of flesh.
“Look, Zengel, as I tried to explain…”
 With a grunt of distaste Strag flung the book across the room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musing in the Podport</title>
      <link>/19-musing-in-the-podport.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/19-musing-in-the-podport.html</guid>
      <description>Gawl and Rambersack were, as ever, in search of new sources of inspiration. Still of persistently limited renown, they were shielded from adverse criticism of their modest contributions to the world’s poetic corpus by sheer self-belief and dogged enthusiasm. They had dabbled with myths, fulminated against biotaps, teased out slender shades of meaning where others might have shrugged with indifference. Now they had set themselves the daunting challenge of summoning their Muse from within the pages of The City Enwitter, one of the flashy fabloids disseminated by Morton Quanderpyre’s media empire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unreliable Rumours</title>
      <link>/20-unreliable-rumours.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20-unreliable-rumours.html</guid>
      <description>A discordant fanfare of trumpets sounded from the presumed taxidermist across the road, drowning out the morning’s first few territorial chirps. It was barely dawn. In the downstairs flat opposite, propped on an elbow from the comfort of her bed, Tannaby squinted blearily up at the unrestored gables, corbels and ornate finials of Old Greenhaddock House. Already eroded by centuries of weather, their outlines were further pleasantly softened by a sympathetic light, the colour of cooked prawns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dundro Fappit&#39;s Mistake</title>
      <link>/21-dundro-fappits-mistake.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/21-dundro-fappits-mistake.html</guid>
      <description>The natives of the Micronesian island of Tao&amp;rsquo;kaua sometimes tell their children the legend of The Jellyfish Who Tried to Eat the Stars. It is one of many cautionary tales they have up their sleeve to instil respect, discourage foolhardiness, and, as a good friend of mine once eloquently put it, &amp;lsquo;knock some of the greth out of the little bastards.&amp;rsquo; As a morally instructive example, The Jellyfish Who Tried to Eat the Stars is about as effective as The Snake Who Lost the Moon, or The More and More Bird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoolocks and Hellions</title>
      <link>/22-hoolocks-and-hellions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/22-hoolocks-and-hellions.html</guid>
      <description>Patella 3rdfield sat in front of the mirror adjusting her ear-rings: spiral swirls of diamond-dust studded with tiny sapphires and rubies held in an invisible cloud of programmed nanogel. She was wearing the deep blue cashmere and silk outfit which Aurelian said matched her eyes. Her dark blonde hair was neatly pinned back. The ear-rings were simplified models, of course, but the accelerated movement was detectable even under quite low magnification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
